Hi! My name is Slava.
And today I am going to talk about Meteor
and your text editors, where you write code.
So, raise your hand if you use one of those:
Vim, Emacs or Sublime Text.
Wow, I think it is like the whole room.
So, this talk is going to be helpful to you.
I hope!
So, my first question is "Why you don't use
Vim?".
I think Vim is the best editor, I know the
whole MDG actually uses Emacs but I am a hardcore
Vim only user.
There are actually some good reasons not to
use Vim for web dev. And some of them are
like... the tool is not just good enough for
JavaScript. And you don't get autocompletion,
jump to definition, all the good stuff that
you are used to in the Java world. Even in
python... even python works well.
Actually, you know, these editors are very
cool, they are not even editors, they are
called IDEs. X-code for Objective-C, Eclipse
for Java and VS for C#. They are great and
companies are investing a lot of money into
them. And that's why these tools are so great.
But Vim is not that bad actually, there are
plenty of plugins those bring you cool features
for C++ or C# or Python.
So it is not really a problem of editor. Editors
are capable of doing that.
I thought there should be a project for JavaScript
that does that. That brings all these static
analysis [features] to your code editor.
And actually there is one. It is called TernJS.
It is written by the author of ACorn and CodeMirror.
They are very good projects. They already
support node.js, angular, jquery, underscore.
And they didn't support Meteor for some reason.
And I thought it is a problem. I took one
weekend off, I've seen this mailing thread
telling us "ok, there is this thing called
TernJS, I think it is really cool". We should
use it.
And I thought "Yeah, we should use it" and
I hacked in one weekend and that is what I
have.
You have smart completion based on your syntax.
For example it knows (I don't know, is it
small?), it knows that it is your collection
and it knows what are the methods on your
collection.
You can jump to definitions. I can go to some
call to my collection and jump to the code
path where this collection is actually defined.
I can get references. Like "Find me all the
places where I use this collection". And does
not just do simple search. It actually does
some analysis on syntax tree to understand
what actually happens.
You can get docs, that I think very important
to have docs when you have a large code base.
Not only docs for Meteor but also docs for
your internal code base.
Type inference. It is probably hard to see
but on the bottom there is a line changing.
Every time I go to a different symbol, it
shows me what type is it. Is it an object?
Is it a collection? Is it like a computation?
And that's what works. I think it is really
cool. We have basic features of TernJS. You
have autocompletion. You have file scoping
for Meteor. It means like if you declare something
in one file it will not be visible in the
second file, unless it is global and it works.
Also we have a lot of definitions for Meteor
and I took it from type definitions for Typescript.
They are actually useful, very useful! Thanks
to all these people who did that.
And we could utillize it in this project for
JavaScript. What doesn't work.
Renaming refactorings don't actually work.
Docs from docs.meteor.com don't actually work.
Packaging scoping doesn't work quite yet,
I am planning to spend another weekend working
on that. And it would be nice if could generate
all these definitions from Meteor, for all
new versions of Meteor. You know, I am not
going to do it manually.
This is the link on GitHub. It is called tern-meteor.
It is just a plugin for Tern system. And actually
works for all these 3 editors. Emacs, Vim
and Sublime Text. I also have instructions
and video screencasts how to install them.
People report that they actually work.
What is next? I want to work on those features
those don't work. I am encouraging people
who want to join me? To contribute? So for
example: you don't actually need to know how
to hack on, I don't know, manipulate ASTs
and stuff like that.
What you can do, you can write definitions
for your favorite packages. I just talked
to Bo from EventedMind. He said he is going
to hack on it and bring definitions for IronRouter,
for example.
And you can do it for your favorite packages
as well like Meteor.Collection2 or like Forms
and stuff like that.
That's it, please use it!